<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>devStory</title>
    <description>Tales from a web developer</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Persist Memory</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Terminal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;
  $ persist-memory --verbose memory-payload.json devstory.db&lt;br /&gt;
  Username: mikec&lt;br /&gt;
  Password:
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;
**Initiating memory upload to persistent storage.**&lt;br /&gt;
Source: Recent Memory&lt;br /&gt;
Destination: devStory Blog&lt;br /&gt;
Payload Size: 18 Months
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;
Printing verbose output. **DISCLAIMER:** The payload size is too large to print out all stored data. Persist Memory will detect the most poignant memories and display data pertinent to those. To force all data to be displayed use the option “--verbose-all”. Also note that memories will not appear in chronological order.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to become complacent once you have a steady job. Why bust your hump on personal projects when you’ve got projects going on at work? Why bother blogging or using Twitter when you could be using that time to unwind after work or prepare for the next day of work? I don’t agree with this way of thinking, but I have fallen victim to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to be a concept artist. It’s been a dream of mine since I was in middle school, and I’ve finally decided to start pursuing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I need to get back to using Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[MEMORY ENCRYPTED. REASON: Confidential]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There can be a large disparity between who you believe you are and how you present yourself. This may seem like an obvious statement, but until you take the time examine what those differences are, you might be fooling yourself into thinking you are someone that you aren’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lack of empathy in the world is extremely disheartening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Docker is amazing! For over a year I’ve been struggling to understand what Docker actually is. Now that I’ve seen what a pain it can be to manage a backend application amongst a team, I’m beginning to understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For several years, I’ve believed that my source of happiness in life was helping others.  While I’ll still believe that’s true to some extent (as it probably is for everyone), I no longer think it’s the most accurate statement. It was nice to think of myself as an altogether selfless person, but I think there was some wishful thinking involved in that conclusion. If I’m being honest, I think my true source of happiness is creativity. I just like to make stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve decided to become a data scientist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just finished two cups of Anxi Qilan tea from the Wuyi mountains of the Fujian province of China. I’m about to brew a couple more. It’s an oolong tea that smells like a field of flowers and tastes like a mixture of honey and vegetables. If you steep it too long, it quickly grows bitter, but an under-steeped cup is more forgiving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[MEMORY ENCRYPTED. REASON: Politically charged]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Admittedly, intuition isn’t a reliable source of information. It can’t be quantified, graphed, or otherwise analyzed. It is an individual, abstract thing with no conceivable probability of success or failure to anyone other than the intuition-er. Therefore, it’s easy to say that no one should rely on intuition. Heck, who even knows if intuition exists? It’s probably just a word for unconscious thought culminating in a semi-logical conclusion. The fact is, we all feel some form of intuition. So, we can either choose to use it or ignore it. I choose to use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s way past time for me to start blogging again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I might be a stoic. Before today, I didn’t even know what stoicism was, but I think I’m a stoic now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve never thought to compare religion and philosophy, but they’re very closely related. If someone chooses to conform to a way of life based on a philosophical belief, how is that any different from following a religion? I’m sure it’s more nuanced than that, but it seems like an apt comparison.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why should I pursue art or writing when it is more practical for me to spend my time building applications? I love sketching and I love creating stories, but investing into a skill that already makes me money is simply too practical to ignore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should really start tweeting again. I’m also going to start working on a blog post tonight. And I’m going to actually publish it this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Python is a fantastic language. Don’t tell anyone else I said this, but I might like it even more than JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Complacency is killing me. I need to do something crazy. Wait. No. Not crazy. Something…different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[MEMORY ENCRYPTED. REASON: Game of Thrones spoilers]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do we love React because it’s better or because it was first? I mean, React is very well established and probably isn’t going anywhere. But Vue is pretty dope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My current perspective on the human condition: No matter how many ways people rephrase the idea “Money can’t buy happiness,” people who have not experienced it themselves will not end their pursuit of wealth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m encouraged by my generation’s appreciation for the importance of mental health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I aggressively envy people with an exceptional skill for data visualization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;547.5 days of memories saved (0.1 days of memories printed).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/chapter-8/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/chapter-8/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>#FailMore</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I am proud to say that this chapter was published on one of my favorite web dev blogs, &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/javascript-scene/fail-more-6e7719048618#.7isx9uysr&quot;&gt;Javascript Scene&lt;/a&gt;. Check it out there!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/chapter-7/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/chapter-7/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Heart of 1s and 0s</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I almost forgot about my fascination with AI. It began back in 2001, when I was still in elementary school. My best friend introduced me to a game called Halo: Combat Evolved. The game followed the death-defying journey of a soldier known only as Master Chief as he slayed aliens on the mysterious ring world of Halo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Master Chief was an unmatched fighter, the lone survivor of a government project to create super soldiers. Chief’s only companion—the only ally who dared challenge his authority or ability—was an artificial intelligence named Cortana (the namesake of Microsoft’s not-quite-Siri personal assistant).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t think much of Cortana upon my first time playing Halo. For the most part, she was just a female voice that made cheeky remarks and updated Master Chief on mission objectives. As I became more fascinated by Halo, though, I found that it’s AI characters were of my favorite parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friends made fun of me for reading Halo novels. To them, Halo was just a game. To me, it was an entire universe—a universe filled with space battles, military tactics, valor, and future technology. It was my first love affair with science fiction. As I got older and began to move away from Halo and deeper into sci-fi and fantasy, I always found it impossible for me to imagine a future that wasn’t occupied by a race of AI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Toward the end of my senior year of high school, I was accept at Drexel University as a computer science student. I couldn’t wait to dive into Drexel’s AI curriculum. While I was still slugging my way through low-level courses, though, other desires caught my attention. Money pulled me toward computer engineering. Creativity attracted me to web development. Introspection lured me into writing. Over time, I completely forgot I ever wanted to study AI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, not long ago, an idea suddenly came to me. It wasn’t an original idea or a revolutionary one, but it was crystal clear in my mind—more clear than almost any idea I’ve had since I first laid my eyes on Halo. I would build a business around AI. I didn’t know how I would do it, how long it would take, or where to begin, but I knew it just felt right. Then, as if in confirmation from the universe, I discovered chatbots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That pretty much catches us up to today. I’m currently building my first chatbot, a Facebook messenger bot I’ve named Doe Bot. It’s a simple currency converter that probably won’t ever do much more than that. Still, it’s a start. I hope many years from now I will look back on this blog post and remember this as one of the best decisions I’ve ever made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to chatbots, I’m also very interested in machine learning and neural networks. Those technologies are way out of my league right now, but I’m looking forward to working my way up to them. Humanity is still a ways off from building a Cortana-level AI, but I can see the potential. Computers are already beginning to think for themselves and perform tasks that I didn’t think computers were capable of performing. I want to be a part of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t believe that I forgot I want to be a part of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some portion of this blog will now be dedicated to documenting my journey toward building my own Cortana (or Jarvis, because that seems a little less creepy). Considering my negligence in keeping this blog updated over the past few months, I may exclusively post about AI— don’t want to get overambitious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A message to my future self: Hi, Future Mike. I’m about to make you really smart.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/chapter-6/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/chapter-6/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Building APIs</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;A4: Self-reflection helps you keep doing the good things and get rid of the bad things. That&amp;#39;s blogging for me.&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/CodeNewbie?src=hash&quot;&gt;#CodeNewbie&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/iCmLVkvBuT&quot;&gt;https://t.co/iCmLVkvBuT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Mike Cornish (@MikeWCornish) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MikeWCornish/status/786382898807107584&quot;&gt;October 13, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I owe most of my ability as a web developer to bloggers who share their knowledge and experiences. You might wonder why someone would offer valuable information freely, but I’ve found that everyone benefits from sharing information, including the person doing the sharing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to articulate a process or experience, you have to review it in your mind. You have to remember, organize, and filter it so that it makes sense and is useful to other people. That’s why I want to start writing about the things that I build. Yes, I absolutely want other developers to benefit from my experiences, but I’ll get a lot out of it as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first in a series of “appendices” which will detail the lessons I learn while working on different projects. I’ve already written a couple of these types of blog posts (&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@MikeCornish/what-i-learned-while-creating-an-animated-chart-with-d3-js-f4882b79914c#.jksvcdqxg&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@MikeCornish/im-currently-working-my-way-through-the-free-code-camp-assignments-and-i-recently-completed-one-cd086f637e3a#.qvyu3qh7j&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;), but now I’m ready to make it official. Let’s get this started!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;topics&quot;&gt;Topics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#yarn&quot;&gt;Yarn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#express&quot;&gt;ExpressJS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#mongo&quot;&gt;MongoDB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#heroku&quot;&gt;Heroku&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m going to be detailing the lessons I learned while completing 5 API projects from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freecodecamp.com&quot;&gt;Free Code Camp&lt;/a&gt; curriculum. These included building microservices for converting timestamps to dates, parsing request headers, shortening URLs, returning Google image search results, and returning metadata from an uploaded file. Most of the end results are fairly useless, but the process of building them was a fantastic learning experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basic process for each project was the same: Set up with npm/Yarn, create endpoints with Express, manage data with Mongo (if necessary), and deploy to Heroku. After determining that basic process, all of the projects became much easier; I even completed a couple of them on the same day. It took some time to get to that point, though. Here are some reasons why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can view the final products in these repositories:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mCornish/timestamp&quot;&gt;Timestamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mCornish/header-parser&quot;&gt;Header Parser&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mCornish/url-shorterner&quot;&gt;URL Shortener&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mCornish/image-search&quot;&gt;Image Search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mCornish/file-metadata&quot;&gt;File Metadata&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;yarn&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;yarn&quot;&gt;Yarn&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I was working on these projects, Facebook announced the release of &lt;a href=&quot;https://yarnpkg.com/&quot;&gt;Yarn&lt;/a&gt;, a major competitor for npm’s spot as king (queen?) of package management. I won’t pretend to be an expert on the subject, but I do appreciate the waves the announcement made in the community. My Twitter feed was absolutely tangled with Yarn on release day. It’s the first time I’ve seen something affect so much of the web development community in such a dramatic way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For someone like me, who never got deep into npm, it’s easy to equate Yarn with a new syntax for npm; the syntax is the biggest change I’ve noticed so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh, so now it’s &lt;strong&gt;add&lt;/strong&gt; instead of &lt;strong&gt;install&lt;/strong&gt;. That’s confus—I mean, that’s nice.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s obvious that Yarn is much more than a new syntax, but I won’t pretend to be as affected as more advanced developers. Even after reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.facebook.com/posts/1840075619545360/yarn-a-new-package-manager-for-javascript/&quot;&gt;Facebook’s explanation&lt;/a&gt; of why Yarn exists, I can still only muster so much excitement. All the same, I look forward to seeing how the community adapts and whether npm responds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;yarn-resources&quot;&gt;Yarn Resources&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://yarnpkg.com/&quot;&gt;Yarn Official Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://code.facebook.com/posts/1840075619545360/yarn-a-new-package-manager-for-javascript/&quot;&gt;Facebook Announcement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;express&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;expressjs&quot;&gt;ExpressJS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used Express years ago, back when I was first exposed to web apps. Back then, I only used it for routing; I didn’t even know what APIs were. Now, after building several APIs with Express, I’m super interested in what kind of tasks I can simplify with APIs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/azat-co/expressworks&quot;&gt;ExpressWorks&lt;/a&gt; lessons were all I needed to get up and running with Express. It was tempting to skip over some of the lessons that seemed like I could just read and say, “Yeah, I understand that,” but I would highly advise actually taking the time to complete each lesson. There are some speedbumps I could have circumvented if I’d paid closer attention to ExpressWorks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of speedbumps: I encountered an annoying issue where I would receive a request from the /favicon.ico route every time I refreshed my page. A Google search revealed that this is a somewhat common issue with Express that can be remedied with a one-liner:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;app.use(‘/favicon.ico, res =&amp;gt; res.sendStatus(200));
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though Express is an amazing tool that is used all over the place, I don’t have much else to say. It’s satisfyingly straightforward (at least in terms of building APIs) and you can learn everything you need by completing ExpressWorks, then referencing &lt;a href=&quot;http://expressjs.com/en/api.html&quot;&gt;Express’s documentation&lt;/a&gt; when you need it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;expressjs-resources&quot;&gt;ExpressJS Resources&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/azat-co/expressworks&quot;&gt;ExpressWorks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://expressjs.com/en/api.html&quot;&gt;Express API Reference&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;mongo&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mongodb&quot;&gt;MongoDB&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve used Mongo quite a bit for web app development. However, the bulk of my experience comes from using it with MeteorJS, where it is somewhat abstracted. Setting up a project from scratch to use Mongo with Express was a very different experience from using it with Meteor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/iksose/9401758&quot;&gt;This tutorial&lt;/a&gt; was very helpful in getting me off the ground. For me, the most complicated part was figuring out the best way to connect to Mongo in relation to calling my API functions. Ultimately, I connected in index.js and set my endpoints in the callback function, passing in a database object to my API functions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;MongoClient.connect(MONGO_URL, (err, db) =&amp;gt; {
    if (err) {
        console.log(&quot;Unable to connect to Mongo.&quot;);
        process.exit(1);
    } else {
        app.get('/foo', fooFunc.bind(null, db));
        app.get('/bar', barFunc.bind(null, db));

        app.listen(app.get('port'), () =&amp;gt; {
            console.log('Node app is running on port', app.get('port'));
        });
    }
});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, the next big problem was deployment. I used mLab to host my database. Once you create a new database in mLab, you are provided with a URL through which to connect to your database. Simple, right? Not quite. The URL includes a username and password, which you’ll obviously want to keep secret. So, you need your code to use a URL without actually containing the URL. The solution? Environment variables:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;# On Mac/Linux
export MONGOLAB_URI=“mongodb://username:password@foo123.mlab.com:1234/foobardb”
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/FreeCodeCamp/FreeCodeCamp/wiki/Using-MongoDB-And-Deploying-To-Heroku&quot;&gt;This guide&lt;/a&gt; covers everything I needed to know, but I missed one detail: When you set an environment variable in a terminal, you have to use the same terminal window to start your server and use the variable. Since I’m generally using at least two different terminal instances at any given time, this was a huge pain for me. Twice, I sat pulling out my hair as I tried to figure out why index.js couldn’t find my MONGOLAB_URI variable. The devil’s in the details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With my environment variable working locally, all I had to do was push to Heroku and set my environment variable there. This gave me about an hour of trouble because I set the variable to MONGLAB_URL instead of MONGOLAB_URI. Those details—they’ll cost you a lot of time if you’re not careful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mongodb-resources&quot;&gt;MongoDB Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/iksose/9401758&quot;&gt;Creating a REST API using Mongo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/FreeCodeCamp/FreeCodeCamp/wiki/Using-MongoDB-And-Deploying-To-Heroku&quot;&gt;Deploying MongoDB to Heroku&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;heroku&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;heroku&quot;&gt;Heroku&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, I used &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.heroku.com/&quot;&gt;Heroku&lt;/a&gt; to deploy my first ever web app. I don’t remember much about that experience, but I do remember feeling slight trepidation at the idea of using Heroku again. Maybe I had difficulties using the CLI, or maybe I just associate Heroku with the frustrations of building my first app. In any case, I was surprised to find that Heroku was a joy to work with on these API projects. I highly recommend it for deploying node apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I set up my projects to deploy automatically after I pushed to Github, which made the process super simple. It’s all intuitive, fast, and, best of all, free (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.heroku.com/pricing?c=70130000001xDpdAAE&amp;amp;gclid=CjwKEAjw7ZHABRCTr_DV4_ejvgQSJACr-YcwEIGBF2rwo_3KjpWLKVCzBJ7rLak2I9R5U1a1dyrMbBoCaHXw_wcB&quot;&gt;kind of&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish I could share some Heroku pro tips, but I didn’t have to mess with it too much. Be sure to check your logs if you run into any difficulties. Beyond that, you should be able to figure everything out through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://devcenter.heroku.com/categories/nodejs&quot;&gt;official documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/appendix-a/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/appendix-a/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>002</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Curation is vital to how I operate on a daily basis. I learn most of what I know through articles and videos shared via email and Twitter. So, I’ve decided to give back and start my own weekly curated link list. There’s no definite theme yet other than &lt;em&gt;mostly&lt;/em&gt; web development; I’ll refine it more each week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;links&quot;&gt;Links&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;google-fights-pop-ups&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://webmasters.googleblog.com/2016/08/helping-users-easily-access-content-on.html&quot;&gt;Google Fights Pop-ups&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s almost worrying how much power Google holds over the internet, but as long as they keep working in our favor, I suppose we’ll just keep ruling over us. Last month, Google made a play for the hearts of UX designers everywhere by telling everyone’s clients to chill out with the pop-ups because, seriously, your users hate them. I mean, you can do whatever you want, but Google’s going to derank your page if you don’t comply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;web-developer-checklist&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://webdevchecklist.com&quot;&gt;Web Developer Checklist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you regularly make websites from start to finish, you may not need this. Then again, maybe you’ve been missing steps and you don’t know it. Web Developer checklist reminds you of all the steps you probably want to take before sending your project out into the web. I haven’t used it yet, but it seems like a smart bookmark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-new-rules-of-form-design&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.uxbooth.com/articles/the-new-rules-of-form-design/&quot;&gt;The New Rules of Form Design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a million ways to design and build a form, but almost all of them are seriously flawed. If you want to design forms that are proven to work from a UX perspective, this article is a great place to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;create-react-app&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/facebookincubator/create-react-app&quot;&gt;Create React App&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting a new project can be one of the worst parts of web development, especially if you work with a lot of libraries. Automation tools like this one are extremely useful for getting started without the initial speedbump. It’s supported by a lot of great developers, so you can count on it to set you up for success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;git-extras&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tj/git-extras&quot;&gt;Git Extras&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I rarely use git to it’s full potential. Even now, I’m working from my main branch and rarely create branches for anything other than major refactors that I’m afraid might screw up everything. Git Extras makes it easy to follow best practices like creating branches for issues. I’m going to start using it as soon as I finish writing this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;react-faq&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/timarney/react-faq&quot;&gt;React FAQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s another great resource I have bookmarked to use later. I’m not deep into React right now, but I plan to start diving in very soon. I assume this collections of links will prove very useful.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/bibliography-2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/bibliography-2/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The New Kid (Again)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I remember the moment I felt like I might actually belong. Before that moment, I was never fully aware of the importance of community in web development. For years, I was just a web developer; after that moment, I was part of the web development community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure what triggered it. Back then, I was still a novice Twitter user (even now, I’m only alright at it), and my following-to-follower ratio betrayed that I wasn’t anyone special. Yet, one day, a fairly popular Javascript-lover named &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/JS_Cheerleader&quot;&gt;@JS_Cheerleader&lt;/a&gt; followed me on Twitter. I had been following JS_Cheerleader for a couple weeks by that time, and I knew that she (Maybe he? Let’s just say she.) had good taste in content and was followed by a few highly respected developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JS_Cheerleader followed thousands of other people, but I didn’t care; I was among them. I was part of the community. If I could get one person to accept me, why not two, or one hundred? I started tweeting more and more about development and, for the first time, my follower count crept over the sacred 100 mark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.devstory.mikecornish.net/posts/chapter-4/&quot;&gt;I started to wander&lt;/a&gt;. I began tweeting more about writing and less about web development, and eventually I stopped tweeting altogether. Every couple of weeks, when my follower count would take a small dip, I would check to see whether JS_Cheerleader was still following me. Sure enough, every time, she was still there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each time I saw the label informing me that @JS_Cheerleader still “FOLLOWS YOU”, I felt a mixture of pride and shame. I was proud that I still had something I could point to and say, “See? I belong! I’m still a legit developer!” Yet, I also felt like a fraud. I had stopped earning the right to be a member of the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t tweeted about web development in over 5 months. While Twitter holds little jurisdiction over who gets to be a developer, it’s been a very important part of my personal growth. Today, web development is a communal practice. If you try to do it in complete isolation, it’s very unlikely that you’ll make anything that matters. So, while I’ve found that, even after my hiatus, my web dev skills are well intact, I don’t feel the same sense of fulfilment I once felt. I’m on the outside. It’s like I’m the new kid all over again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever I try to think back to the moment I met my friends, I often conclude that we never officially “met” at all. In most cases, we just spent so much time around each other that we built a familiarity that, at no specific moment, became a friendship. If you want to stop being the new kid, all you have to do is keep showing up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution, then, is for me to start getting active in the community again. I need to work up the confidence to start tweeting about web dev. I need to get back to some kind of regular &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twitch.tv/thatnerdygeek&quot;&gt;streaming&lt;/a&gt; schedule. At the start of the year I made a resolution to create my first JavaScript Library; I still have 4 months to make that happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, I was reading over a copyediting assignment for a freelance job and my client requested that I provide feedback on her website if I didn’t mind the extra work. She thought I was just a writer/editor, so she wasn’t expecting the full page of feedback I sent her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was a little reluctant to give her feedback on the website, because I’d been away from web development so long that it felt almost insincere. I couldn’t help myself, though. She had a big ol’ pop-up ad on her homepage that I just had to tell her she should get rid of if she wanted to boost her conversions. That same week, &lt;a href=&quot;https://webmasters.googleblog.com/2016/08/helping-users-easily-access-content-on.html&quot;&gt;Google announced&lt;/a&gt; that they were going to start deranking pages that used disruptive pop-ups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stopped looking for copywriting jobs after that. It became clear to me that I can’t stop being a web developer. I’m still trying to crawl my way back to where I was before, but it just feels…right. I’m the new kid again, but that feeling is as exciting as it is intimidating. Time to get back to work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/chapter-5/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/chapter-5/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Detour</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been chasing my passion since I was a child. In elementary school, I was a compulsive writer, forcing my teachers to comment on every nonsensical short story I wrote. When I got home from school, I would walk up the hill to my best friend’s house and he would illustrate comic books as I wrote the plot. In middle school, I became obsessed with creating music. I was a top clarinet player in our school band, and I begged my mother buy me a keyboard, then a guitar, then an electric guitar, then a bass guitar. In high school, I started at least 5 different blogs. By the time I reached college, I was addicted to web development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Passion is what drives my work ethic, my energy, and my ambition. If my free time wasn’t occupied by activities that I deeply care about, I don’t know what I’d do with myself. Yet, I think I’ve reached a point where it’s no longer a good idea to follow my passion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Main Road (Practicality)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love web development, but I’ve never fully appreciated it as much more than a safety net. My life’s goal is to become a great author. Unfortunately, development doesn’t fit neatly into that equation. I need web dev, though, because it’s far more practical to my livelihood than writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t study English in college. I didn’t study writing or journalism or publishing. I studied computer engineering, then switched to computer science, and finally landed in digital media and web technology. While passion informed my decisions to choose and switch my majors, it wasn’t my north star. Instead, I have always tried to follow the path of practicality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Web development is my main road. If I stay on this path, it’s very likely that I’ll be able to live a happy, productive life. I can get a good job, meet wonderful people, eventually start my own business, and contribute to society—all things I really care about achieving. Somewhere in my mind, though, my passion says that’s not quite good enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Detour (Passion)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People have been complimenting my writing for years. English was always my favorite class in school because I found it extremely easy and, even in college, I was often singled out by the teachers as an exceptional writer. I don’t mention this to brag (especially since you’re currently reading my writing and probably aren’t impressed); I mention it to explain why some part of my mind knows, without a doubt, that I’m meant to be a writer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few months ago, I diverged from web development. Passion whispered from the bushes on the side of the road and coaxed me into following it to a magical place called Fiverr. Fiverr is a freelancing website that allows you to easily sell your skills. Initially, I convinced myself that it was a great place to make money from my web dev experience. Soon enough, though, the real reason for the detour became apparent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it turned out, it was really easy for me to get work as writer through Fiverr. As I completed jobs, my buyers threw more compliments my way and, after a few months, my service was reaching a point where demand outweighed supply. Sounds amazing, right? Not quite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my time on Fiverr, I was making less than minimum wage. To put that differently: My very first job as a web developer paid over 75% better than my freelancing adventure on Fiverr, and I was arguably doing an easier, more meaningful job when I was a developer. My detour became so rife with uncertainty that my passion-driven escapade became almost completely devoid of passion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I had stuck it out, my detour probably would’ve join up with a new major road that would allow me to keep moving happily through live. I couldn’t wait that long, though. I was in a time and place in my life where that kind of risk wasn’t practical. I stopped, turned around, and headed back for the main road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Getting Back on Track&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think many people (especially my fellow millennials) insist on chasing their passion because their pride won’t settle for anything less. If they’re like me, some part of them knows they’re capable of more than checkout lines, customer service desks, and cubicles. They know that, by simply accepting the safety of the main road, they’ll be giving up the adventure, the risk, and the reward of the detour. We all believe we deserve more, and maybe we do, but that doesn’t justify the foolishness of chasing your passion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mike Rowe, host of Dirty Jobs and blue collar advocate, once said to “never follow your passion, but always take it with you.” That message has stayed with me ever since I first heard it. Even as someone who has written several articles about the importance of following your passion, I now see the impracticality of passion’s pursuit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, I’m working my way back into web dev. Writing this blog post is actually one of my first steps to figuring out what I want to do. Before I went on my detour, I was livestreaming the process of getting my frontend web development certification. I really enjoyed doing that and I’d like to get back to it. I only have one assignment left before I get my certificate, but I can certainly find other projects to stream once that’s finished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the while, I’ll be keeping my passion with me. I’m finally rewriting my first novel, and I’ll be doing some freelance editing on the side. I’ll be maintaining this blog and perhaps starting another one. I love writing, and I don’t think anything could ever keep me from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a final note: A huge shout out to Gary Vaynerchuk for giving me the kick in the ass I needed to finally write this blog post. If you consider yourself ambitious or entrepreneurial, you need to get familiar with Gary; his wisdom is life-changing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/chapter-4/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/chapter-4/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>World-Changers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There are two kinds of people on this planet: Those who are changed by the world and those who change the world. Some people are happy to simply exist on this planet and seek stability. These are the people who prefer not to rock the boat and cling to the popular way of doing things. They conform, because it’s easier, and perhaps even smarter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, there are people like us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“People like who? Who’s not smart? I want to be smart.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Web developers and designers tend to fall into the second category of people. Many of us are creatives who didn’t enter this career just to make money. We want to help people or express ourselves or change the whole damn world. And that’s exactly how it &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, it’s just not in our nature to be subversive. And, no, we’re often not smart in our approach to making a difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“O…kay…so you’re calling me stupid.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me give you an example of what I mean. Last week, two popular YouTubers called the Fine Brothers announced that they were creating a network called React World, whereby other YouTubers could work with them to create offshoots of Fine Brothers content. However, they didn’t explain it like this at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Fine Brothers’ announcement video, which has since been removed (you can find re-uploads on YouTube pretty easily), focused on the exact wrong thing: Legality. The video is laced with legal terms and several outright uses of the word “legal”. That, combined with their over-the-moon tone was enough to send the internet into an uproar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One major source of backlash was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/videos/comments/43490c/the_fine_bros_from_youtube_are_now_attempting_to/&quot;&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt;, a website infamous for it’s tendency to generate hive minds and incite witch hunts. In less than a day, the Fine Brothers went from regarded YouTubers to some of the most hated people on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the most important part, though: &lt;strong&gt;Despite having little or no understanding of the situation, many people were outwardly angry at the Fine Brothers.&lt;/strong&gt; Most people didn’t fully understand what the Brothers were trying to accomplish, or how they were trying to do it. No one could claim to know their true intentions, which I personally think were probably harmless. In fact, the Fine Brothers explicitly said they were trying to make the world a better place, but they presented their approach so poorly that no one was listening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time they made a video further explaining React World in an attempt to patch things up, the mob was already in full effect. It just fueled the fire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In true internet fashion, people made personal attacks on the Brothers. Unsubscribing from their channel became a celebrated act. A few popular YouTubers even hopped on board, berating the Fine Brothers because they knew it was the popular thing to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s blowing over now that React World has been canceled, but quite a few haters are still lingering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Nice story, but can you get to the point? Isn’t this a blog about web development?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The significance here is that web developers exist on the same conformist internet as the Fine Brothers. When even a good-intentioned mistake can make you the focus of overwhelming hate, it can be scary, and even dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to change the world, not unlike the Fine Brothers. And, frankly, we want to make money from our hard work, not unlike the Fine Brothers. It’s not difficult to imagine that, if we move too far from the herd, we could get just as burned as the Brothers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we’re diligent, though, &lt;strong&gt;we can use that conformity to our advantage&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mob mentality and herd behavior are just a part of human nature (for more info on this, watch &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lrf6xuFq1Ms&quot;&gt;Coders are herd animals&lt;/a&gt;). More than a few times, I’ve caught myself being swayed by popular opinion on Reddit or YouTube. It’s up to us, the world-changers, to combat that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We shouldn’t just watch for trends, we should actively engage with them—analyze them, criticize them, and even create them&lt;/strong&gt;. Influencers ganged up on the Fine Brothers because it was the hot thing to do, but wouldn’t it have been just as hot to play devil’s advocate?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“This is noble and everything, but you said yourself that I want to make money. How do I apply this to my professional practices?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, attention is money. If you’re leading a herd, you’re controlling the market. The bigger the herd, the bigger the gains and the losses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re just following the popular trends and opinions, you shouldn’t expect to be the next Bill Gates, Mark Zuckerberg or Elon Musk. If you want to be great, you have to make a serious effort to be different. You can’t just pay attention to where the market is, you have to know where it’s going. Then, you have to act on that knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why you’re a world-&lt;em&gt;changer&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Could you be a little more specific? Perhaps share your thoughts in a convenient list format?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Never stop solving problems:&lt;/strong&gt; Problems are the best source of innovation. Take note of things that bug you or piss you off, then fix them.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Share your thoughts:&lt;/strong&gt; If you want to lead a herd, you have to give people a reason to follow. Start a blog or YouTube channel. Tweet. Speak up.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Promote open-minded content:&lt;/strong&gt; The internet can really suck, but you can help make it better. Share content from world-changers who engage in conversation instead of regurgitating popular opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t forget to cash in:&lt;/strong&gt; You can’t survive on good intentions. Help people and share your knowledge, but don’t forget to sell something when the time is right. If you don’t understand this, you really need to read &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Jab-Right-Hook-Story-Social/dp/006227306X/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1454938988&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=jab+jab+jab+right+hook&quot;&gt;Jab, Jab, Jab, Right Hook&lt;/a&gt; by Gary Vaynerchuk.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell stories:&lt;/strong&gt; People think in stories. If you want to be heard, learn how to communicate in stories. I highly recommend &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/The-Storytelling-Animal-Stories-Human/dp/0544002342&quot;&gt;The Storytelling Animal&lt;/a&gt; by Jonathan Gottschall.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve made it this far you should recognize that you’re probably a world-changer by nature. Don’t let yourself be content with the status quo. The status quo sucks: Have you seen the state of the world? We can do better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make yourself heard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are you a world-changer? Don’t know how to shake conformity? Want more book recommendations? Leave a comment and we can talk!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/chapter-3/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/chapter-3/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Mobile Diet</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The first time I used Snapchat, it felt &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt;. I’m not talking specifically about sending a picture or sharing a video; I’m talking about the overall experience. Navigating the layouts. Adding my first few friends. Recording my first Snap. It all felt new and, for lack of a better term, it all felt &lt;em&gt;slim&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Snapchat’s design isn’t perfect, but it did accomplish something very important: It made me want to keep using it. I’ve briefly examined why I wanted to revisit the app again and again, and I’ve summed it up as a design principle I call Slim Design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&quot;You're creating principles now? Where did *that* come from?&quot;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like most developers, I grew up in a world where apps and smart devices didn’t exist. I took my first plunge into the internet on my family’s clunky living room computer. I had my own PC when I started writing my first lines of HTML and CSS. By the time I traded in my flip phone for a smart phone in 2011, I had a pretty solid idea of how a good website looked and functioned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around the time I started seriously learning to create websites, responsive design was claiming the design throne. Sensationalists were already declaring the death of the desktop computer. Long live the Mobile Devices! I didn’t really understand the hype: My PC still worked way better than my phone, and I had no plans to stop using it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&quot;But not you're all about mobile? What made you change your mind?&quot;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never changed my mind. I still believe desktop computers are better for most tasks—have you tried writing an essay on a phone? However, mobile devices have inspired a new type of design that is rarely accomplished on desktop. &lt;strong&gt;It’s slim.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be clear: When I say design, I’m not just talking about how it looks. Modern mobile apps are designed to be simple and fun to &lt;em&gt;use&lt;/em&gt;. The &lt;strong&gt;experience&lt;/strong&gt; is slim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Snapchat, it’s easy to open the app, accomplish a task, and move on with your day in no more than a few minutes. That’s not just because of its highly spatial layout or its simplistic camera interface. It’s just designed to be quick. The whole premise of Snapchat is speed. Fast things also tend to be slim and trim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&quot;Would you shut up about Snapchat? Snapchat is for weirdos and teenagers.&quot;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t be quick to spurn Snapchat because of its reputation. It’s not Facebook or Twitter, but that’s what makes it great. That’s exactly what makes modern mobile apps so full of opportunity: They’re not the user experiences we grew up with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mobile apps don’t need bulky navigation menus or sidebars or headers or footers. They only need enough elements to get the job done quickly and enjoyably. They don’t ask you to stick around for a while. They give you what you need and tell you to get the hell out, knowing that you’ll come back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&quot;So...what? Desktop apps aren't rude enough for you?&quot;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Desktop apps, also known as web apps, carry the weight of history and tradition. They’re bulky because they’re made to harbor your attention and gather your sweet, sweet clicks. If traditional businesses had their way, we’d never leave their websites. Modern, mobile, slim businesses know we don’t have the attention span for that anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mobile apps respect your time and attention. Snapchat gave us temporary content. Vine gave us super short videos. Twitter, ahead of its time, forced us to be concise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&quot;Vine and Twitter are also on desktop, though. Get your facts straight!&quot;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slim Design, as I’m going to trend-settingly call it, isn’t exclusive to mobile devices—that’s just where it originated. Eventually, I don’t think websites and web apps will have a choice but to slim down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one has time to search through your website anymore. We don’t want drop-downs, accordions, carousels, or even hamburgers. We want to &lt;a href=&quot;http://jobstobedone.info&quot;&gt;get a job done&lt;/a&gt;, and we want to do it quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&quot;How do I accomplish Slim Design?&quot;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s a big question, which I’d love to answer in-depth another time. Honestly, though, I’m not entirely sure. I’m neither a seasoned designer nor a mobile developer. I’m certainly working my way into the mobile space, but there is a lot to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now, I’d just recommend familiarizing yourself with modern mobile apps. If you don’t already, start using some on a regular basis. Hop on Snapchat; add me (@mikewcornish). We didn’t grow up with mobile apps, so we have to intentionally teach ourselves what they’re all about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;How do you feel about Slim Design? Is it even a thing? Leave a comment and let me know!&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/chapter-2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/chapter-2/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>001</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Curation is vital to how I operate on a daily basis. I learn most of what I know through articles and videos shared via email and Twitter. So, I’ve decided to give back and start my own weekly curated link list. There’s no definite theme yet other than &lt;em&gt;mostly&lt;/em&gt; web development; I’ll refine it more each week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;links&quot;&gt;Links&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;meteor-guide&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://guide.meteor.com&quot;&gt;Meteor Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been building apps with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.meteor.com&quot;&gt;MeteorJS&lt;/a&gt; for almost a year now. In that time, it has become clear that a major limitation of Meteor is that it isn’t opinionated. There is no “Meteor Way” to build apps. Meteor Guide is a step in the right direction, offering Meteor developers a common way of handling popular problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;velocity-react&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/twitter-fabric/velocity-react&quot;&gt;Velocity-React&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve only recently started looking into UI animation. Though I haven’t had a chance to actually use &lt;a href=&quot;http://julian.com/research/velocity/&quot;&gt;VelocityJS&lt;/a&gt; yet, this integration with React makes me excited to give it a try. Making animations from scratch can be less than thrilling, and I’d be happy to do away with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-i-left-gulp-and-grunt-for-npm-scripts&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@housecor/why-i-left-gulp-and-grunt-for-npm-scripts-3d6853dd22b8#.xkw6bxg3y&quot;&gt;Why I Left Gulp and Grunt for npm Scripts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though I haven’t used &lt;a href=&quot;http://gulpjs.com&quot;&gt;GulpJS&lt;/a&gt; much recently, I have used it often in the past and recognize its utility. I find it interesting that a step backward toward &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.com&quot;&gt;NPM&lt;/a&gt; seems to actually be taking a step forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-the-difference-between-class--prototypal-inheritance&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/javascript-scene/master-the-javascript-interview-what-s-the-difference-between-class-prototypal-inheritance-e4cd0a7562e9#.vsmk7q14h&quot;&gt;What’s the Difference Between Class &amp;amp; Prototypal Inheritance?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eric Elliot has been blowing my mind lately. He’s very good at explaining important and complicated Javascript topics in a way that an intermediate developer can understand. You should absolutely catch up with his &lt;em&gt;Master the Javascript Interview&lt;/em&gt; series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;variables-the-backbone-of-css-architecture&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2016/01/variables-in-css-architecture/&quot;&gt;Variables: The Backbone of CSS Architecture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get an unusual amount of pleasure out of having ultra-maintainable CSS. This article highlights one way that thoughtful CSS can greatly improve the process of developing and maintaining a project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lostpass&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.seancassidy.me/lostpass.html&quot;&gt;LostPass&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you use LastPass, you’re definitely going to want to read about this vulnerability (and maybe consider using a different password manager). I love when programmers take controversial action for a good cause.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dailyvee&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLfA33-E9P7FA-A72QKBw3noWuQbaVXqSD&quot;&gt;DailyVee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re an entrepreneur, you should be following Gary Vaynerchuk. He isn’t a web developer, but he’s one hell of a businessman and he loves to share his knowledge (for FREE). I highly encourage you to watch the first episode of DailyVee and see whether you’re interested in more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-the-voices-behind-your-favorite-games-and-show-are-inventing-live-dd&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.polygon.com/features/2016/1/11/10589378/how-the-voices-behind-your-favorite-games-and-shows-are-re-inventing&quot;&gt;How the Voices Behind Your Favorite Games and Show Are Inventing Live D&amp;amp;D&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve never tried to hide the fact that I’m a geek. In fact, I basically started my web development career on that fact. Well, nothing is much geekier than &lt;a href=&quot;http://geekandsundry.com/shows/critical-role/&quot;&gt;Critical Role&lt;/a&gt;. It’s D&amp;amp;D with fantastic voice actors, and it’s easily my favorite show right now. Read this Polygon article to learn more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;top-tweets&quot;&gt;Top Tweets&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;I&amp;#39;m asking the candidates a question in tonight’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/DemDebate?src=hash&quot;&gt;#DemDebate&lt;/a&gt;! Streams live at 9PM EST here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/frxUhFho9Y&quot;&gt;https://t.co/frxUhFho9Y&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/DCkQpJBEBp&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/DCkQpJBEBp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Marques Brownlee (@MKBHD) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MKBHD/status/688901276625670144&quot;&gt;January 18, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;To help my friend reach publishing goal, I&amp;#39;m including a signed headshot with each Hardback order, up to 750 sales!&amp;#10;&lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/Ieyyc9kNMk&quot;&gt;https://t.co/Ieyyc9kNMk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Felicia Day (@feliciaday) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/feliciaday/status/689530657177874432&quot;&gt;January 19, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Investigating a bug &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/GjY5xb7vww&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/GjY5xb7vww&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Practical Developer (@ThePracticalDev) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ThePracticalDev/status/689456670611640320&quot;&gt;January 19, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/bibliography-1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/bibliography-1/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>